MEKTOUBI ZAKARIA

+36 20 582 2914 ♦ Budapest, Hungary

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with two years of experience in solving real-world problems using machine learning models and data-driven solutions in projects related to computer vision and time series forecasting. Experienced in implementing machine learning pipelines that include data collection, data pre-processing, model implementation, training, monitoring, and deployment on the cloud.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science for Autonomous Systems,

2020-

Faculty of Informatics, Eötvös Loránd University - Budapest, Hungary.

Master of Data Science,

2018-2020

Faculty of Sciences, Cadi-Ayyad University - Marrakech, Morocco.

Bachelor of Informatics and Decisional Systems Engineering.,

2014 - 2018

College of Technology - Berrechid, Morocco

High School Diploma in Mathematical science.,

2012 - 2013

Oum-Hani High School - Marrakech, Morocco.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

Apr 2022 - Present

Tata Consultancy Services TCS - Becton, Dickinson BD

Budapest, Hungary

- Develop Machine Learning models for forecasting using **ARIMA**(Autoregressive Integrated Moving Average) and **Prophet** models.
- Develop an **MLOps** framework to automate the ML model training process, and the deployment to production following CI/CD best practices.
- Technologies: Python, Pytorch, Azure ML, Azure DevOps.

Machine Learning Scientist

Mars 2020 - Sept 2020

Computer Science Lab - Cady Ayyad University

Marrakech, Morocco

- Develop a **deep learning** model for **food recognition**, deployed on a mobile application capable of recognizing the type of dish from a single image and providing various information (recipe, nutritional value, and tutorial video).
- Technologies: Python, Beautifulsoup, Pandas, Pytorch, OpenCV, FastAPI, Azure machine learning.

Data Scientist Intern CIMR

July 2019 - Sept 2019

Casablanca - Morocco

- Implement a data preprocessing pipeline to Extract, Transform, and Load large datasets to Mysql Data warehouse.
- Develop a BI solution to generate daily dynamic reports using PowerBI
- Technologies: Python, SQL, BeautifulSoup, pandas, Flask, Mysql, PowerBI.

Business Intelligence Engineer Intern Saham Insurance

Apr 2018 - June 2018

Casablanca - Morocco

- Modeling and Developing **ETL** workflow to support and monitor Bancassurance activity.
- Technologies: MS BI(SSIS, SSAS), Power BI.

PROJECTS

• Develop Machine Learning Models for NER(Named Entity Recognition), Topic Classification, and discritization of Arabic newspaper articles, Deployed as a web service.

Technologies: Farasa, Scikit-Learn, spacy, Beautiful Soup, Regex, FastAPI.

SKILLS

Programming Python, SQL, C++

ML Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, TensorFlow

Data Manipulation Pandas, Geopandas, Pyspark, NumPy, OpenCV, Scipy, Spacy, Nltk

BI ETL, MS BI, Pentaho DI

Visualization Tableau, PoweBI

Azure Services Azure Machine Learning, Azure DevOps, Azure data factory, Azure synapse Analytics.

Others Docker, Git, Terraform, Airflow, MLflow.

CERTIFICATIONS

• DP-900: Azure Fundamentals.

INTERESTS

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

NLP

Computer Vision

CI/CD

 ${\rm DevOps/MLOps}$

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- French Fluent
- Arabic Native
- Hungarian Beginner